<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Machine Learning on Rihad Variawa</title>
    <link>/categories/machine-learning/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Machine Learning on Rihad Variawa</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2019</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 07 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/machine-learning/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Bank ATM Cash Machine Forecast w/ Time Series</title>
      <link>/post/atm/bank/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/atm/bank/</guid>
      <description>Preamble: This document focuses on the time series analysis. The variable ‘Cash’ is provided in hundreds of dollars.
This is a time series spanning daily transactions from May 1, 2009 to April 30, 2010 from four ATMs.
 Research question: forecast how much cash is taken out of 4 different ATM machines for May 2010   Structure of analysis: Exploratory Data Analysis Visualizations ACF and PACF Clean The Data Trend Preview Data Decomposition Plot Stationarity Test Model Data Transformation ARIMA Model Evaluation Box-Ljung Test Forecasting Model Accuracy  sourceURL &amp;lt;- &amp;quot;https://raw.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Energy Forecasting w/ Time Series Analysis</title>
      <link>/post/residential_energy/residential-energy-usage/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/residential_energy/residential-energy-usage/</guid>
      <description>Preamble: This document focuses on the time series analysis. A simple dataset of residential power usage from January 1998 to December 2013.
 Research question: through an analysis, model this data and monthly forecast for 2014   Structure of analysis: Exploratory Data Analysis Visualizations ACF and PACF Clean The Data Trend Preview Data Decomposition Plot Stationarity Test Model Data Transformation ARIMA Model Evaluation Box-Ljung Test Forecasting Model Accuracy  sourceURL &amp;lt;- &amp;quot;https://raw.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Energy Demand Analysis w/ Time Series Forecasting</title>
      <link>/post/energyd/energy-demand-analysis-w-time-series-forecasting/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/energyd/energy-demand-analysis-w-time-series-forecasting/</guid>
      <description>References:  R. H. Shumway, D. S. Stoffer. Time Series Analysis and Its Applications. 2010. R. J. Hyndman. Forecasting: principles and practice. 2013. P. S. P. Cowpertwait, A. V. Metcalfe. Introductory Time Series with R. 2009.  Preamble: This document focuses on an analysis of the energy demands of a European country.
The dataset of the daily energy needs (in GWh) between 2004 and 2010.
 Reseach questions: build a model for energy demand forecasting using time series analysis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Time Series Analysis</title>
      <link>/post/time_series_ap/time-series-analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/time_series_ap/time-series-analysis/</guid>
      <description>Preamble: This document focuses on the analysis of the airpassengers dataframe.
The AirPassenger dataset in R provides monthly totals of US airline passengers, from 1949 to 1960.
Description of dataframe airpassengers can be found at https://stat.ethz.ch/R-manual/R-devel/library/datasets/html/airpassengers.html
 Research question: through analysis and modelling, preview a time series forecast   Structure of analysis: I will asssess whether a linear regression or arima model is a best fit for the time series forecast as follows:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Predict the diamond price based on the 4 c&#39;s</title>
      <link>/project/diamonds/predict-the-diamond-price-based-on-the-4-c-s/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/diamonds/predict-the-diamond-price-based-on-the-4-c-s/</guid>
      <description>Preamble: This document focuses on the analysis of the diamonds data frame.
Descriotion of data frame diamonds can be found at https://stat.ethz.ch/R-manual/R-devel/library/datasets/html/diamonds.html
 Research questions: am i getting a fair deal when I purchase a diamond?
 The goal is to build a predictive model for diamonds, that is going to help figure out whether a given diamond is a good deal or a rip-off!
   Structure of analysis: I will use Linear Regression to predict the diamond price using other varaibles in the diamonds dataframe.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>