<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Machine Learning on Rihad Variawa</title>
    <link>/categories/machine-learning/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Machine Learning on Rihad Variawa</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2019</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 31 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/machine-learning/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Time Series Analysis</title>
      <link>/post/time_series_ap/time-series-analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/time_series_ap/time-series-analysis/</guid>
      <description>Preamble: This document focuses on the analysis of the airpassengers dataframe.
The AirPassenger dataset in R provides monthly totals of US airline passengers, from 1949 to 1960.
Description of dataframe airpassengers can be found at https://stat.ethz.ch/R-manual/R-devel/library/datasets/html/airpassengers.html
 Research question: through analysis and modelling, preview a time series forecast   Structure of analysis: I will asssess whether a linear regression or arima model is a best fit for the time series forecast as follows:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Predict the diamond price based on the 4 c&#39;s</title>
      <link>/project/diamonds/predict-the-diamond-price-based-on-the-4-c-s/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/diamonds/predict-the-diamond-price-based-on-the-4-c-s/</guid>
      <description>Preamble: This document focuses on the analysis of the diamonds data frame.
Descriotion of data frame diamonds can be found at https://stat.ethz.ch/R-manual/R-devel/library/datasets/html/diamonds.html
 Research questions: am i getting a fair deal when I purchase a diamond?
 The goal is to build a predictive model for diamonds, that is going to help figure out whether a given diamond is a good deal or a rip-off!
   Structure of analysis: I will use Linear Regression to predict the diamond price using other varaibles in the diamonds dataframe.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Machine Learning using linear regression to predict house prices</title>
      <link>/project/machine_learning_using_lr/machine-learning-using-linear-regression-to-predict-house-prices/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/machine_learning_using_lr/machine-learning-using-linear-regression-to-predict-house-prices/</guid>
      <description> Intro &amp;amp; Background Linear regression being one of the most basic and popular algorithms in machine learning, so when aspiring data scientist starts off in this field, linear regression is inevitably the first algorithm they come across.
 Analysis Approach You can click on the link below to see the working code in Python and reproduce it to test the strength of your own password.
https://github.com/2series/100_Days_of_ML_Code/blob/master/Linear_Regression_from_Scratch.ipynb
 </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>