<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Rihad Variawa</title>
    <link>/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Rihad Variawa</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2020</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Analyzing Historical Default Rates of Lending Club Notes</title>
      <link>/post/lendingclub/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/lendingclub/</guid>
      <description>The code
Lending Club is the world&amp;rsquo;s largest peer-to-peer lending company, offering a platform for borrowers and lenders to work directly with one another, eliminating the need for a financial intermediary like a bank.
Removing the middle-man generally allows both borrowers and lenders to benefit from better interest rates than they otherwise would, which makes peer-to-peer lending an attractive proposition.
This post will be the first in a series of posts analyzing the probability of default and expected return of Lending Club notes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AI Augmenting Compliance</title>
      <link>/post/augmentingcompliance/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/augmentingcompliance/</guid>
      <description>Forming a significant theme in several organisational technology strategies, AI can augment a gamut of business practices, including compliance Compliance is a must-do activity, not a nice-to-have. It is essential that companies extract maximum value from compliance processes, reducing the possibility of it being considered a cost centre.
Technological innovation can help to lift some of the compliance burden. The level of technology you can realistically implement depends on how advanced the organisation is to start with.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Privacy &amp; Security in the Age of Machine Learning</title>
      <link>/post/privacysecurity/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/privacysecurity/</guid>
      <description>Can we adequately protect the privacy and security of data used in machine learning? As the adoption of machine learning (ML) increases, it is becoming clear that ML poses new privacy and security challenges that are difficult to prevent in practice. This leaves the data involved in ML exposed to risks in ways that are frequently misunderstood.
While traditional software systems already have standard best practices such as the FIPPs (Fair Information Practice Principles) to guide privacy efforts, or the Confidentiality, Integrity and Availability triad to guide security activities, there exists no widely accepted best practices for the data involved in ML.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NLP applied in Deep Learning</title>
      <link>/post/nlp/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/nlp/</guid>
      <description>Deep Learning applied to natural language processing  Language is the medium that humans use for conversing. Giving machines the ability to learn human language with natural language processing has given rise to several new products and possibilities that were not previously imaginable.
 NLP (Natural language processing) is one of the most important technologies present in the information age. Understanding complex language utterances is a crucial part of Ai.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Movies Recommender System</title>
      <link>/post/moviesrecommender/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/moviesrecommender/</guid>
      <description>Here&amp;rsquo;s the app accompanying this blog
The code
As the Internet gets more and more popular, information overload poses an important challenge for a lot of online services. With all of the information pouring out from the web, users can be overwhelmed and confused as to what, exactly, they should be paying attention. A recommendation system provides a solution when a lot of useful content becomes too much of a good thing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Should Ai Intimidate Us?</title>
      <link>/post/shoulditintimidateus/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/shoulditintimidateus/</guid>
      <description>Recently major plays in the technology industry have been talking about why the potential applications of artificial intelligence could be something we should be worried about. Their argument comes from two different places. On the one hand, they see Ai as one of the most fundamental transformative technologies that we have ever seen in the history of mankind, and on the other hand, that transformative power is something we should be scared of and be wary about.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cash Reward Payments</title>
      <link>/post/cardrewardpayments/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/cardrewardpayments/</guid>
      <description>Retailers, big tech’s and fintechs are fighting back against cash-reward cards.
Attending a recent outing with family and friends at a Yankees playoff game, I ordered a round of food and drinks and paid for it using cash back from my Apple credit card. It felt like we all got free hot dogs and beverages.
Love of credit card rewards is as American as baseball, and in no other market do rewards hold as much sway as in the U.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Machine Learning relationship with AI</title>
      <link>/post/mlai/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/mlai/</guid>
      <description>Of the many downsides to the recent revival and popularity of Ai (Artificial Intelligence) one is that we see a lot of vendors, professional services firms, and end users jumping on the Ai bandwagon branding their technologies, products, service offerings, and projects as Ai products, projects, or offerings without it necessarily being the case. On the one side, there isn’t a well-accepted delineation between what is definitely Ai and what is definitely not Ai.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data Science Life Cycle</title>
      <link>/post/ds/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/ds/</guid>
      <description>Data Science Life Cycle Data science is quickly evolving to be one of the hottest fields in the technology industry. With rapid advancements in computational performance that now allow for the analysis of massive datasets, we can uncover patterns and insights about user behavior and world trends to an unprecedented extent.
With the influx of buzzwords in the field of data science and relevant fields, a common question I’ve heard from friends is “Data science sounds pretty cool — how do I get started?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ai Common Sense</title>
      <link>/post/biasadded/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/biasadded/</guid>
      <description>One of the biggest challenges with artificial intelligence and data science is the integrity of our data. Even if we did all the right things in our models, and our testing, data might conform to some technical standard of “cleanliness,” there might still be biases in our data as well as “common sense” challenges. With Big Data, it is difficult to get to a certain granularity of data validity without proper real-world testing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AI Hype. Don&#39;t Be Fooled</title>
      <link>/post/aihype.-dont-be-fooled/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/aihype.-dont-be-fooled/</guid>
      <description>The Ai Hype Train Has Left the Station We know we’re in the middle of a hype cycle when every industry has products that use some buzzword, regardless of whether or not they have the technical merit or legitimacy to actually use that buzzword. This is where we currently are with regards to the market for Ai (Artificial Intelligence) products and services.
We hear briefings from vendors pitching technology across a wide range of solution areas, as well as from professional services and government contracting firms with new solution offerings and end users looking for guidance and advice.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thinking AI?</title>
      <link>/post/thinkingai/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/thinkingai/</guid>
      <description>Science and Sci-fi can’t seem to agree on the way we should think about artificial intelligence. Sci-fi wants to portray artificial intelligence agents as thinking machines, while organizations today use Ai for more mundane tasks like filling out forms with robotic process automation or driving your car. When interacting with these Ai interfaces at our current level of Ai technology, our human inclination is to treat them like vending machines, rather than to treat them like a human.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Paper To Digital Intelligence</title>
      <link>/post/papertodigital/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/papertodigital/</guid>
      <description>Organizations use paper. Businesses in every vertical have always relied upon a certain quantity of paper since the dawn of time and, despite the rise of digital, that basic truth isn’t going to change. Although invoices are now largely digital, boarding passes live on smartphones and there’s even an app (or two) for To-Do lists and notepads, a certain amount of paper will always feature as part of any firm’s operational tasks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blockchain &amp; Ai</title>
      <link>/post/blockchainai/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/blockchainai/</guid>
      <description>Artificial Intelligence (Ai) as a market is full of hype, with vendors, customers, and press all speaking breathlessly about the capabilities for Ai in general and their offerings specifically. Likewise, blockchain is also a widely hyped market, with technology providers and customers claiming all sorts of capabilities that may or may not be possible. Combining Ai and blockchain then must be double the hype? On the other hand, Ai is providing real, tangible value in many myriad ways we talk about every day.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blockchain Aids the World&#39;s Largest Organizations Innovate Securely</title>
      <link>/post/innovesecurely/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/innovesecurely/</guid>
      <description>Much like the internet, the rise of blockchain gives individuals and organizations the chance to achieve vast improvements in productivity. For instance, blockchain can improve transactional processes among individuals, companies, suppliers and legislators to create more scalable, efficient solutions.
The Appeal Blockchain is a decentralized, distributed ledger of transactions that has elements of transparency, trust, verifiability, and something called smart contracts. Decentralized and distributed means that information that is stored across the network in such a way that each end point has access to the data without requiring access to a central server.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ai Deployment In FinTech</title>
      <link>/post/insurance/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/insurance/</guid>
      <description>It’s no secret the insurance industry is primed for disruption. All you need to do is type terms like “ai for insurance” or “latest insurtech” into Google search, and a veritable cornucopia of articles will pop up preaching the advantages of adopting new, intelligent technologies. With so much information available, it’s no wonder many insurers are struggling to figure out how to embark on their Ai journey in a way that ensures projects yield the desired results.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ai Essential</title>
      <link>/post/aiessential/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/aiessential/</guid>
      <description>Companies widely recognize the potential power of artificial intelligence (Ai). They instinctively understand that it feels like we’re on the cusp of something that will change our lives and our businesses in a profound way. Yet, many struggle with where to apply it. Executives can’t shake the feeling that they should have use cases for Ai and use it productively today, even recognizing that Ai is not mature yet and will be far more powerful tomorrow and in the future.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Known Unknowns</title>
      <link>/post/knownunkowns/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/knownunkowns/</guid>
      <description>Data Scientists have a strange predicament in an age of Ai: They are meant to solve problems for companies by marshaling the relevant data on customers and transactions, but the data itself is going to raise new, unexpected questions.
Increasingly, the data that is relevant for companies’ Ai system efforts will be not just some data, but all of it; anything less risks missing what could conceivably be the critical insight down the road, the answer to questions as yet unasked.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Poker Face Is Better Than You Think</title>
      <link>/post/illusionoftransparency/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/illusionoftransparency/</guid>
      <description>We tend to think that people can easily tell what we’re thinking and feeling. They can’t. Understanding the illusion of transparency bias can improve relationships, career performance, and more.
“A wonderful fact to reflect upon, that every human creature is constituted to be that profound secret and mystery to every other.” ― Charles Dickens, A Tale of Two Cities
When we experience strong emotions, we tend to think it’s obvious to other humans, especially those who know us well.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Free, Invisible &amp; Instant Payments</title>
      <link>/post/freeinvisibleinstantpayments/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/freeinvisibleinstantpayments/</guid>
      <description>My morning ritual on days when I work in Manhattan is to get off the train at Grand Central Station, use my phone to order my coffee on the Starbucks app with an invisible pre-funded payment, and then join the crowd at the pickup line. I’m not alone: Mobile Order and Pay represents 12% of Starbucks’ U.S. payments and more people use Starbucks’ proprietary payment system than use Apple Pay.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Great Conspiracy Against Us</title>
      <link>/post/hanlonrazor/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/hanlonrazor/</guid>
      <description>If you ever feel that the world is against you, you are not alone.
We all have a tendency to assume that when anything goes wrong, the fault lies within some great conspiracy against us. A co-worker fails to give you a report in time? They must be trying to derail your career and beat you to a promotion. Your child drops and breaks an expensive plate? They must be trying to annoy you and waste your time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Do I Know If My Model Is Good?</title>
      <link>/post/modeltest/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/modeltest/</guid>
      <description>One of the most common lines of questioning from data scientists today goes something like this: “How do I know if my model is good? Should I just take R^2 score? Should I take AUC? What does it mean for a given model to know if it’s good or not?”
The best way to decide whether or not a model is good is to have the business interests directly plugged into that decision.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why Humans Can Never Do One Thing</title>
      <link>/post/externalities/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/externalities/</guid>
      <description>No action exists in a vacuum. There are ripples that have consequences that we can and can’t see. Here are the three types of externalities that can help us guide our actions so they don’t come back to bite us.
An externality affects someone without them agreeing to it. As with unintended consequences, externalities can be positive or negative. Understanding the types of externalities and the impact they have in our lives can help us improve our decision making, and how we interact with the world.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stories That Shape Our Reality</title>
      <link>/post/stories/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/stories/</guid>
      <description>We can select truths that engage people and inspire action, or we can deploy truths that deliberately mislead. Truth comes in many forms, and experienced communicators can exploit its variability to shape our impression of reality.
The truth is not as straightforward as it seems. There are many truths, some of them more honest than others. “On most issues,” writes Hector Macdonald in his book Truth: How the Many Sides to Every Story Shape Our Reality, “there are multiple truths we can choose to communicate.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Probabilistic Value</title>
      <link>/post/probabilisticvalues/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/probabilisticvalues/</guid>
      <description>Probabilistic thinking is essentially trying to estimate, using some tools of math and logic, the likelihood of any specific outcome coming to pass. It is one of the best tools we have to improve the accuracy of our models. In a world where each moment is determined by an infinitely complex set of factors, probabilistic thinking helps us identify the most likely outcomes. When we know these our decisions can be more precise and effective.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Statistics To Reduce Deadweight From Our Lives</title>
      <link>/post/deadweight/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/deadweight/</guid>
      <description>“Knowledge is indeed highly subjective, but we can quantify it with a bet. The amount we wager shows how much we believe in something.” — Sharon Bertsch McGrayne
The quality of your life will, to a large extent, be decided by whom you elect to spend your time with. Supportive, caring, and funny are great attributes in friends and lovers. Unceasingly negative cynics who chip away at your self-esteem? We need to jettison those people as far and fast as we can.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>