<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Rihad Variawa</title>
    <link>/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Rihad Variawa</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2020</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 06 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Should Ai Intimidate Us?</title>
      <link>/post/ai-should-it-intimidate-us/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/ai-should-it-intimidate-us/</guid>
      <description>Recently major plays in the technology industry have been talking about why the potential applications of artificial intelligence could be something we should be worried about. Their argument comes from two different places. On the one hand, they see Ai as one of the most fundamental transformative technologies that we have ever seen in the history of mankind, and on the other hand, that transformative power is something we should be scared of and be wary about.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ai Common Sense</title>
      <link>/post/ai-bias-added/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/ai-bias-added/</guid>
      <description>One of the biggest challenges with artificial intelligence and data science is the integrity of our data. Even if we did all the right things in our models, and our testing, data might conform to some technical standard of “cleanliness,” there might still be biases in our data as well as “common sense” challenges. With Big Data, it is difficult to get to a certain granularity of data validity without proper real-world testing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thinking AI?</title>
      <link>/post/thinking-ai/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/thinking-ai/</guid>
      <description>Science and Sci-fi can’t seem to agree on the way we should think about artificial intelligence. Sci-fi wants to portray artificial intelligence agents as thinking machines, while organizations today use Ai for more mundane tasks like filling out forms with robotic process automation or driving your car. When interacting with these Ai interfaces at our current level of Ai technology, our human inclination is to treat them like vending machines, rather than to treat them like a human.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Paper To Digital Intelligence</title>
      <link>/post/paper-to-digital-intelligence/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/paper-to-digital-intelligence/</guid>
      <description>Organizations use paper. Businesses in every vertical have always relied upon a certain quantity of paper since the dawn of time and, despite the rise of digital, that basic truth isn’t going to change. Although invoices are now largely digital, boarding passes live on smartphones and there’s even an app (or two) for To-Do lists and notepads, a certain amount of paper will always feature as part of any firm’s operational tasks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blockchain &amp; Ai</title>
      <link>/post/blockchain-ai/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/blockchain-ai/</guid>
      <description>Artificial Intelligence (Ai) as a market is full of hype, with vendors, customers, and press all speaking breathlessly about the capabilities for Ai in general and their offerings specifically. Likewise, blockchain is also a widely hyped market, with technology providers and customers claiming all sorts of capabilities that may or may not be possible. Combining Ai and blockchain then must be double the hype? On the other hand, Ai is providing real, tangible value in many myriad ways we talk about every day.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ai Essential</title>
      <link>/post/ai-essential/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/ai-essential/</guid>
      <description>Companies widely recognize the potential power of artificial intelligence (Ai). They instinctively understand that it feels like we’re on the cusp of something that will change our lives and our businesses in a profound way. Yet, many struggle with where to apply it. Executives can’t shake the feeling that they should have use cases for Ai and use it productively today, even recognizing that Ai is not mature yet and will be far more powerful tomorrow and in the future.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>