<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects on Rihad Variawa</title>
    <link>/project/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Projects on Rihad Variawa</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2019</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 25 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/project/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Predict the diamond price based on the 4 c&#39;s</title>
      <link>/project/diamonds/predict-the-diamond-price-based-on-the-4-c-s/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/diamonds/predict-the-diamond-price-based-on-the-4-c-s/</guid>
      <description>Preamble: This document focuses on the analysis of the diamonds data frame.
Descriotion of data frame diamonds can be found at https://stat.ethz.ch/R-manual/R-devel/library/datasets/html/diamonds.html
 Research questions: am i getting a fair deal when I purchase a diamond?
 The goal is to build a predictive model for diamonds, that is going to help figure out whether a given diamond is a good deal or a rip-off!
   Structure of analysis: I will use Linear Regression to predict the diamond price using other varaibles in the diamonds dataframe.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data Tidying Project</title>
      <link>/project/data_tidying/data-tidying-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/data_tidying/data-tidying-project/</guid>
      <description>Introduction The data hosted at [data.world] and contains information about Sales in the US.
 Get Data Data Set 1: Sales from the Retail Trade and Food Services Report from the US Census. This dataset only covers Department Stores, though the report covers a wide range of retail types. [1992-2016]
Data Set 2 US Retail Sales by Store Type with Growth Rate [2009-2014]
#1992-2016 #https://data.world/retail/department-store-sales GET(&amp;quot;https://query.data.world/s/gdk7iwtlisq6vkktmybqqr7hjjty5s&amp;quot;, write_disk(tf &amp;lt;- tempfile(fileext = &amp;quot;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Machine Learning using linear regression to predict house prices</title>
      <link>/project/machine_learning_using_lr/machine-learning-using-linear-regression-to-predict-house-prices/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/machine_learning_using_lr/machine-learning-using-linear-regression-to-predict-house-prices/</guid>
      <description> Intro &amp;amp; Background Linear regression being one of the most basic and popular algorithms in machine learning, so when aspiring data scientist starts off in this field, linear regression is inevitably the first algorithm they come across.
 Analysis Approach You can click on the link below to see the working code in Python and reproduce it to test the strength of your own password.
https://github.com/2series/100_Days_of_ML_Code/blob/master/Linear_Regression_from_Scratch.ipynb
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build A Simple Blockchain</title>
      <link>/project/simple_blockchain-project/build-a-simple-blockchain/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/simple_blockchain-project/build-a-simple-blockchain/</guid>
      <description>Intro &amp;amp; Background Blockchain is a data structure that was first introduced by Satoshi Nakamoto in the Bitcoin protocol white paper a decade ago. Bitcoin’s blockchain stores transaction data, but we can store any type of data in a blockchain.
Ethereum, for example, enables users to store code snippets called ‘smart contracts’ in their blockchain. In this project, I build a simple blockchain in Python that uses proof-of-work consensus, just like the Bitcoin protocol does.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Password Detection Strength</title>
      <link>/project/password_detection_strength/password-detection-strength/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/password_detection_strength/password-detection-strength/</guid>
      <description>Intro &amp;amp; Background A function written that uses regular expressions to make sure the password string it is passed is strong. A strong password is defined as one that is at least eight characters long, contains both uppercase and lowercase characters, and has at least one digit. You may need to test the string against multiple regex patterns to validate its strength.
 Analysis Approach You can click on the link below to see the working code in Python and reproduce it to test the strength of your own password.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/project/ts_analysis/readme/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/ts_analysis/readme/</guid>
      <description>ts_analysis airpassengers dataframe</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AirPassengers Time Series Analysis</title>
      <link>/project/ts_analysis/code/final_code/airpassengers_ts_analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/ts_analysis/code/final_code/airpassengers_ts_analysis/</guid>
      <description>Preamble: This document focuses on the analysis of the airpassengers dataframe.
The AirPassenger dataset in R provides monthly totals of US airline passengers, from 1949 to 1960.
Description of dataframe airpassengers can be found at https://stat.ethz.ch/R-manual/R-devel/library/datasets/html/airpassengers.html
 Research question: through analysis and modelling, preview a time series forecast   Structure of analysis: I will asssess whether a linear regression or arima model is a best fit for the time series forecast as follows:</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>