<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>R on Rihad Variawa</title>
    <link>/categories/r/</link>
    <description>Recent content in R on Rihad Variawa</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2019</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 31 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/r/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Time Series Analysis</title>
      <link>/post/time_series_ap/time-series-analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/time_series_ap/time-series-analysis/</guid>
      <description>Preamble: This document focuses on the analysis of the airpassengers dataframe.
The AirPassenger dataset in R provides monthly totals of US airline passengers, from 1949 to 1960.
Description of dataframe airpassengers can be found at https://stat.ethz.ch/R-manual/R-devel/library/datasets/html/airpassengers.html
 Research question: through analysis and modelling, preview a time series forecast   Structure of analysis: I will asssess whether a linear regression or arima model is a best fit for the time series forecast as follows:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Predict the diamond price based on the 4 c&#39;s</title>
      <link>/project/diamonds/predict-the-diamond-price-based-on-the-4-c-s/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/diamonds/predict-the-diamond-price-based-on-the-4-c-s/</guid>
      <description>Preamble: This document focuses on the analysis of the diamonds data frame.
Descriotion of data frame diamonds can be found at https://stat.ethz.ch/R-manual/R-devel/library/datasets/html/diamonds.html
 Research questions: am i getting a fair deal when I purchase a diamond?
 The goal is to build a predictive model for diamonds, that is going to help figure out whether a given diamond is a good deal or a rip-off!
   Structure of analysis: I will use Linear Regression to predict the diamond price using other varaibles in the diamonds dataframe.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data Tidying Project</title>
      <link>/project/data_tidying/data-tidying-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/data_tidying/data-tidying-project/</guid>
      <description>Introduction The data hosted at [data.world] and contains information about Sales in the US.
 Get Data Data Set 1: Sales from the Retail Trade and Food Services Report from the US Census. This dataset only covers Department Stores, though the report covers a wide range of retail types. [1992-2016]
Data Set 2 US Retail Sales by Store Type with Growth Rate [2009-2014]
#1992-2016 #https://data.world/retail/department-store-sales GET(&amp;quot;https://query.data.world/s/gdk7iwtlisq6vkktmybqqr7hjjty5s&amp;quot;, write_disk(tf &amp;lt;- tempfile(fileext = &amp;quot;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>mtcars Data Analysis</title>
      <link>/post/mtcars/2019-01-03-r-rmarkdown/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Jan 2019 21:13:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/mtcars/2019-01-03-r-rmarkdown/</guid>
      <description>Preamble: This document focuses on the analysis of the mtcars dataframe.
Description of dataframe mtcars can be found at https://stat.ethz.ch/R-manual/R-devel/library/datasets/html/mtcars.html
 Research questions: is a vehicle with auto or manual transmission better in terms of miles p/gallons(mpg)?
 quantify the (mpg) difference between auto &amp;amp; manual transmission.
   Structure of analysis: I will asssess both queries from different perspectives employing a set of methodologies that can be broadly grouped as follows:</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>